Kuldipsinh Parmar

Surat, Gujarat, India



kuldipdarbar23@gmail.com



8401002194



linkedin.com/in/kuldipsinh-parmar-b3116a45

Summary

I am expert on Web development with Many years of professional experience, complex database Web Development and Web Designing. I love new challenges and learn new technologies very quickly if needed. I am very good with cross platform Frameworks as well.

I have executed many international projects for my client, I have good written and verbal communication skill in English. I am a strong person with excellent motivation skills and a record of delivering projects that are on schedule and within scope requirements.

Experience



Senior Web Developer

Strategic Alliance, India

Feb 2019 - Present (2 years 5 months +)

- Selling automotive restoration items. stock thousands of classic Chrysler, Ford and GM fasteners weighing in at over 1 million pounds.
- Make Rest API for Order pizza, pasta, burgers, Indian or delicious Chinesee dishes online in numerous cities within Germany.
- Digital attendance for gym using face detection and fetch daily reportt.
- Make site for specific community includes login, family details, communityy functions, leaders of community.
- Design and implementation of web applications, CMS-like sites, news sites, tools for offline content edition and sync, web services/APIs integration.
- Developed responsive web pages and interactive charts displaying thee user activity on the product.
- Developed web services for new modules and optimized the existing web services.
- Mentored less experienced developers on a regular basis.
- Improved application core functionality with jQuery for a better customerr experience



Senior Web Developer

Siliconbrix Systems Private Limited

Aug 2017 - Dec 2018 (1 year 5 months)

- Designed reports for the above systems using MYSQL reporting services.
- Responsible for testing ERP applications for validity of results, accuracy, reliability, and conformance to established standards.
- Project scheduling, designing, estimating, and strong interaction
- Conducted the whole system database design and implementation and maintained database system.
- SDLC: Involved from design, test and implementation.

- Developed and modified the front end of the web application by JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax
- Product lifecycle management supply chain management, warehouse management, customer relationship management, sales order processing.
- Mentored and provided guidelines for junior software engineers.



🚵 Junior Web Developer

White Orange Software

Apr 2017 - Jul 2017 (4 months)

- Developed prototypes with HTML5, Javascript and CSS for a customer support application utilizing the wordpress framework.
- Creates custom user interfaces and other site assets based on client directions.
- Collaborated with customer for product requirements.

Mentored and provided guidelines for junior software engineers.

Senior Web Developer

City Broadband

Nov 2015 - Dec 2016 (1 year 2 months)

- Assign every ticket to a specific agent and group so there is no confusion about who should be working on which ticket.
- Filter tickets based on specific properties so the most important tickets that agents should work on are front and center.
- SMS/OTP portals that prompt the users to enter their mobile numbers and then use the SMS method to deliver OTP to the user's mobile phone.
- The OTP/PIN number will be used to logged.
- This is a two-step process in which user's mobile is verified before useris given Internet access.
- Add a portal plan for SMS/OTP portal. This plan will decide the restrictions on user's free session.
- Admin can configure time, bandwidth, device and concurrency restrictions on the plan.

Junior Web Developer

Innovizia Technology

Apr 2015 - Nov 2015 (8 months)

- Developed UI website prototypes in wordpress that are responsive.
- Designed and developed a solution to create and track To-Do lists for sales consultants.
- Creates custom user interfaces and other site assets based on client directions

Project Training

Burning Desire Technologies

Nov 2014 - Apr 2015 (6 months)

Taken project training in magento framework. also customise existing site and add products to backend base on client requirement

Education



Gujarat University

Master in Computer Application, Computer Science

2012 - 2016

Gujarat University

Bachelor of Computer Applications, Computer Science 2009 - 2012

Skills

PHP • WordPress • CodeIgniter • Laravel • jQuery • Bootstrap • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • HTML5